You are being watched.
The government has
a secret system,
a machine that spies on you
every hour of every day.
I know because
I built it.
I designed the machine
to detect acts of terror,
but it sees everything...
Violent crimes
involving ordinary people,
people like you,
crimes the government
considered irrelevant.
They wouldn't act,
so I decided I would.
But I needed a partner--
Someone with the skills
to intervene.
Hunted by the authorities,
we work in secret.
You'll never find us.
But victim or perpetrator,
if you're number's up,
we'll find you.
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
He's on his way there now.
What do we assume he knows?
Assume he knows everything.
All luggage and cartons
must be attended at all times.
Any items left unattended
will be removed by,
subject search
by the MTA Police.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Final boarding call
for the eastbound express--
Track 18.
Final boarding call,
eastbound express-- Track 18.
All aboard.
No, thanks.
I don't drink coffee.
Sencha green tea...
One sugar.
You've been paying attention.
Relax, Finch.
It's just tea.
I haven't guessed
your favorite color yet.
New number...
Wallace Negel.
Born in Germany, 1946,
immigrated to the US in 1980,
worked
in international export--
Good credit, perfect taxes.
Wait a minute.
Are these dates right?
You noticed.
Negel hasn't made
a single electronic transaction
in his own name
since December of 1987.
So where has
he been for 24 years?
And why is he back?
I don't think there is a Negel.
Foreign background,
boring life,
a job involving travel--
Spycraft 101.
This is an alias.
I've used dozens of them.
I think Negel is a cover.
So, where do we start?
Shortly before
he disappeared in 1987,
Negel purchased a cemetery plot
in the Bronx.
I've checked.
It's still there.
Why does
a person who doesn't exist
need a cemetery plot?
Right?
- Might be worth a look.
- Hmm.
Where are you going?
If we're dealing
with a spy from the 1980s,
I know someone
who can provide us
with the kind of pre-digital
information we need--
Things I can't find
on computers.
All first editions,
the best available
on German history.
The entire span
of the cold war would do it,
but specifically, the 1980s.
And I'll be needing something
more precise than books.
I'm not sure what you mean.
How about the Soviet submarine
schematics that you sold
back to Russian intelligence
last year?
You register that income
with the IRS, FBI?
It'd be hard to run this store
from prison, don't you think?
Row 18,
plot 20.
Hmm.
What was the name?
- Wallace Negel.
- Yeah.
Before the country reunified,
east Germany was the greatest
surveillance state
the world has seen.
The Stasi knew everything.
I've read about them.
I'm a sucker for surveillance.
They had millions
of hours of wiretaps,
sweat and body-odor samples.
I just need a name
to go with an alias.
Real name Ulrich Kohl--
Part of an espionage team.
I've read
about the Stasi teams--
Kohl's unit
went around the world,
in and out of Western Europe
and the US.
That's why he needed
the American papers.
The team hunted down
east German defectors
and neutralized them
before they could talk.
"Neutralized."
Where guys like him went,
people died.
Um...
How did you know
about the submarine schematics?
Told you...
I'm a sucker for surveillance.
Looks like Kohl was in Europe
when the wall fell.
Western authorities
were hunting him,
so he ran to hide
in the Soviet Union.
His wife, Anja,
who worked as a secretary
at Stasi headquarters,
ran with him,
but she was killed
in a car accident shortly after.
That was in 1987.
By '89, east Germany
has collapsed.
The Stasi no longer exists,
and Kohl...
Was never heard from again.
Well, he's here now.
Negel's cemetery plot--
It was a buried stash kit.
He dug it up a few hours ago.
What do you think was in it?
If it was anything
like the ones I used to bury,
IDs, weapons, definitely money.
So it seems Kohl,
the spy, is back.
Hauffe.
Sorry?
Can I help you?
It can't be you.
We have something to discuss.
You're the new guy, right?
Let's go somewhere private
so we can talk.
You're Stanton?
I'm--
No, you're not.
The ID NCS gave you
didn't pass muster,
so you're nobody,
which means I get to name you.
Wilson, maybe.
No.
You should have a drink.
I don't drink when I'm working.
No?
Well, start.
You tier one boys
are all the same--
Tense.
Out here,
"tense" gets us killed.
In your old job,
you were behind enemy lines
for 6, 12 months?
In this job, you never go back,
because there is no line
to cross back over.
Never was.
Understand?
So you may as well
get comfortable.
When you were in transit,
did you see any old friends?
No.
Why are you asking?
We know
about the ex-girlfriend.
Like I told you,
you never go back.
The coin Kohl dropped...
Was an east German mark.
They've been out of circulation
everywhere since 1990,
but I found a rare-coin
exchange in the city
where a whole set of marks
was sold this morning.
Let me guess,
the seller was Ulrich Kohl.
Correct.
He used the store's phone,
waited for an answer, hung up.
I traced the call to that
address in the west village--
Apartment 4A.
Finch, we're too late.
Kohl called to make sure
he was home.
He was interrogated.
I'm going through
more of these records.
Kohl was part
of a four man team.
He shared trigger duties
with a team leader
named Steiller.
They were backed by a document
forger named Wernick...
Ah.
And they reported
to a case officer
named Hauffe for orders.
So who's this dead guy?
The apartment
is leased to Andrew Honem--
An unmarried,
retired architect.
Kohl's job
was killing defectors.
Sounds like this guy
might have been one.
Hang on, Finch.
Half the intelligence services
in the world
were tracking
these guys at one point.
But they were ghosts--
Untraceable.
Finch, what was the case
officer's name again?
Hauffe.
This dead guy was Hauffe.
Kohl killed his Stasi teammate.
And he will kill again.
I don't know who you are
or how you know to be here,
but this is just the beginning.
Then this is gonna be
a long day.
Finch, I got company.
BND--
German intelligence.
He seemed to know
what went down here.
He also seemed sure
Kohl would kill again.
Detective Fusco.
Anonymous tip for you, Lionel.
You got to stop
calling me here.
Homicide in the west village.
I think the shooter might have
others planned today.
I left you a care package
at the scene.
I need you to find out
whatever he knows.
Yeah, well, I can't do anything
till someone calls in a crime.
You'll get a call--
"Shots fired."
Were there shots fired?
There were now.
Hauffe's dead.
Who's next on Kohl's hit list?
I took an encrypted phone
from that German agent.
Every text is blocked except
for the one they were reading--
Julian Werner.
Werner is a Wall Street lawyer,
and...
Werner is really Wernick--
The forger.
Kohl's entire team is living
under aliases in New York.
The perfect place
to disappear, right, Finch?
These people
were his teammates.
Why would he be hunting them
two decades later?
Kohl vanishes without a trace,
and his teammates end up
living cushy lives in New York.
This could be revenge
for something--
Maybe more than we know.
- The wife's death?
- The car crash.
She died in '87,
the same year he disappeared.
And I know a staged accident
when I see it.
We need to get to Wernick
before Kohl does.
I thought you were dead.
Still with the needle, I see.
What is it coated with?
Something fast.
It's the least I could do
for an old colleague.
How long have I got?
Long enough.
Where is your accent,
Hauptmann?
We were advised...
To blend in America.
I saw Hauffe this morning.
He was a good case officer.
He kept information on you
all these years.
Do you remember...
My Anja?
I called Werner's assistant.
He has lunch
at the same place every day.
I'm on my way.
I remember.
I didn't know they would go
after her, too.
But killing me won't bring
her back, Ulrich.
I told her
I would keep her safe.
What happened to you, Ulrich?
I paid...
For my sins,
for yours, for the team.
The people who caught me
kept me in a hole,
but I never stopped thinking,
planning.
It was long ago.
I let myself forget.
I did not have that luxury.
It was wrong what we did.
You'll go after Steiller next?
Then...
Be at peace, my old friend.
Call 911.
I need an ambulance
at 43 19th street--
Craftbar Cafe.
Ma'am, stand back, please.
Excuse me.
Weak pulse, but tachycardic--
BP is 70/30.
Shallow respiration,
signs of internal asphyxia.
Convulsions--
Guy's having a seizure.
Hey!
You can't breathe.
You have foam in your nose
and your mouth.
It's hydrocyanic acid.
Now, they're going to find us
in four minutes.
I can save you,
but you need to talk.
What did Kohl come for?
Why is he after all of you?
Kohl was killing
their informants.
The Americans wanted him gone.
So you gave them Kohl.
They offered us a new life.
We traded Ulrich.
You were his team...
His friends.
A soldier deserves better.
I give you these, and you live.
What happened
after you defected?
They told us
Kohl ran to the Soviets--
He and Anja.
The Americans went for him.
They got her, too.
The car accident.
Yes.
Who will Kohl go after next?
St--
Steiller...
He defected
with the rest of you?
Hey?
What's his alias?
I kept the lawyer alive,
but Kohl's not done yet.
Kohl's team betrayed him,
and it got his wife killed.
They preserved themselves
over him.
This is as personal as it gets.
So where's Steiller?
Finch, I saw the exact same pin
in Hauffe's apartment.
The Volks American Society...
Is an organization
for New York citizens
of German heritage.
When the Stasi team defected,
they wouldn't have been allowed
to contact each other.
A German organization
would give all three
a chance to meet in public.
So, if Hauffe and Wernick
were members...
Then Steiller
would have been, too.
There are two crime scenes--
One in the West Village,
the other near Wall Street.
Now, the same senior citizen
wearing a gray suit
was seen fleeing
both locations.
Wall Street?
That's where the ambulance
was jacked earlier, right?
It sure was.
Read the description
of who jacked it?
My guy?
How's he involved in this?
And this guy was found
unconscious at the first scene.
Nice bruises.
He say anything yet,
like who kicked
his ass sideways?
Yeah, two words--
"Phone call."
Everything else is in German.
Either of these guys
look familiar to you?
Now, we know
you're German intel.
We know a lot.
If that's all you know,
polizei,
then you don't know very much.
Yeah, why don't you tell me
about your homicidal geriatric?
Two crimes,
a very dangerous man at work,
and one agent trying
to stop a killer?
It'd be a shame if we polizei
couldn't help.
His name is Kohl.
He is a prisoner...
Arrested in an operation between
my government and yours
24 years ago.
He had become old,
feeble, they thought.
The order was given
to transfer him
to a minimum security facility.
And I'm guessing he escaped.
He's smart and lethal.
And he killed Germans
for years.
There is nothing more important
than putting him back
where he belongs.
Why not involve US authorities?
He was jailed without trial.
Kohl isn't supposed to exist.
No one wants
an international incident.
You aren't supposed to be
operating on US soil.
Where he goes,
people will keep dying.
Then help us.
We want the same thing.
Don't say another word.
Hey, whoa,
this is an interrogation.
- You can't be in here.
- This interview is over.
I am from the German consulate,
and this is
from the US State Department--
Orders to extradite him
back to Germany immediately.
The Volks American website
wasn't even using
an open SSH secure proxy.
I cloned their log-in form
in seconds.
Finch, the point?
I found the complete
membership roster.
Hauffe and Wernick
are both on it.
I'm running background checks
on the other members.
Here...
Michael Stegans--
Construction foreman
from Newark.
Credit scores
only go back to 1988.
If the pattern follows...
Then Stegans
is really Steiller.
He's running a construction
site in Brooklyn.
I have a cell phone.
Hello?
Mr. Steiller?
I'm sorry.
I-I think you have
the wrong number.
There's no time for games.
You need to listen.
Do you remember Ulrich Kohl?
He remembers you.
Just like he remembered
all his old Stasi colleagues.
He's on his way.
You're speaking of a dead man.
I knew this day would come.
You were too good.
I learned from the best.
I learned from you.
You were my friend.
You knew me.
You knew my wife.
She trusted you
as much as I did.
You changed, Ulrich.
I watched what
the missions did to you--
The darkness in your eyes.
You believed in the killing.
You trained me.
You made me what I was.
I believed in my country.
I believed in you.
We could not save you.
So you left Anja
and me to the hounds...
For some money and an apartment
in New York City?
I had to get out.
I was strong.
I survived.
What they did
to Anja, though...
You will pay for that.
Wait.
Wait, Ulrich.
There is something
you don't know.
I was the only one who knew.
Hello?
Anja is alive?
She found me a few years
after we all defected.
She was more afraid of you
than anyone, Ulrich.
So, you see,
your revenge
was all for nothing.
Finch, we need to find Anja.
I think Kohl just added her
to his list.
The car accident was faked.
He was his wife,
and she betrayed him.
To a man like Kohl,
that makes her
just as much a target.
We got a killer out there,
and our best lead
is getting deported.
You still got your vigilante
looking for the shooter.
That's not bad news.
You can't send a killer
to catch a killer, detective.
Hey, your guy
still gets results.
They'll take side streets
to the airport--
Standard procedure.
Tell detective Fusco to send
the GPS tracker number
for the consulate car.
I found their position,
Mr. Reese,
but how do you intend
to stop them?
Mr. Reese, I'm highly
uncomfortable being here.
I'm highly uncomfortable
having you here,
but I need a spotter.
Range it.
I don't know.
500 yards?
600.
45-degree oblique wind...
3/4 value wind speed.
Very impressive, Finch.
What if you miss?
I wouldn't know.
Never have.
Stop.
We have diplomatic immunity.
- I'm not a diplomat.
- Who are you?
I'm the guy who still has time
to save Anja Kohl.
Now, I know she's alive,
but I need to know where.
This man has nothing to say.
Any communication
would violate--
There's nothing I can do.
Save her if you can.
Anna Klein-- An address
in Morningside Heights.
It's Anja.
Anja isn't here, Kohl.
She's safe...
Where you can't get to her.
That's a Welrod, isn't it?
Only 73 decibels when fired.
But it won't stop me
before I get to you.
And I lose my patience
when I get shot.
Wo ist Anja?
What's your plan, Kohl, hmm?
You gonna kill her, too...
Your own wife?
You don't have a plan, do you?
Your external
carotid arteries--
Obstruct both...
And you wake up
with quite a headache.
Ulrich?
It can't be.
He's coming for me, isn't he?
Yes.
What's important now is getting
you into police custody.
There's a detective
at the eighth precinct--
No, wait.
We can't go yet.
It's safe there.
I promise.
Not yet, please.
I need to make a phone call.
A camera...
It's extraordinary.
The Stasi would have killed
for this technology.
Wo ist Anja?
When you travel,
you pick up things--
Skills...
Items.
They all laughed at me
when I learned
to use these needles.
They didn't laugh for long.
I was, uh...
Bagged by an insurgent patrol
when I was in Kandahar.
They used electricity on me...
16 hours.
All they wanted was my name.
I don't care for your name.
The ulnar nerve
is the largest nerve
in the human body
that is unprotected.
It goes from the shoulder,
to the fingernail beds,
when it passes
through the elbow,
it's known as the funny bone.
Wo ist Anja?
Relax.
We're on the same team.
And besides, where would
I hide a gun in this dress?
You're Stanton, right?
Who's this?
Haven't decided yet.
Miller said you like bourbon.
You know what they drink here?
Plum brandy.
- A shame about Miller.
- What happened to him?
Wasn't getting the job done.
Word came down--
Time to take the gloves off.
So...
What can we do for you?
We're looking into reports
that Alim Assir
was in country last week,
possibly to secure financing.
We sent all of our intel
in the pouch
to Langley last week.
And Assir made it
out of the country safely
two days ago.
We want to know how.
That's also in our intel.
Like we said, he must have paid
customs a fortune.
And how much did he pay you?
Kidding.
It's like I said--
You boys are too tense.
Here's to taking
the gloves off.
You've got to be kidding me.
They didn't get very far,
did they?
Thank you.
Remember our friend,
the German agent
and his escort to JFK?
Apparently a guy in a suit
shot them off the road
with a high-caliber weapon.
I'm going to the scene,
see if my guy left a trail
that leads to Kohl.
- Detective Fusco.
- I need your help.
Look...
First him, now you.
Look, you guys just can't ring
me up like I'm a bellhop.
Our mutual friend
went after your perpetrator,
and I haven't heard from him--
Something's wrong.
This man may be more dangerous
than we anticipated.
I need you to check on--
Look, I'm doing everything
I can to convince Carter
your boy's not a problem.
Now you want me
to just walk off the job?
Then you need to figure
something out-- It's urgent.
I'm sending you an address.
Not getting a response?
I know you don't know me,
but I'm someone who can help.
You're gonna have
to kill me, Kohl.
Nobody enjoys taking life.
Killing is what I was good at.
I noticed.
That hydrogen cyanide
that you used on Wernick--
You didn't bring that
into the country.
You bought that here
and mixed it yourself...
Didn't you?
You're...
Familiar with poisons?
Oh, I've had some experience.
I have taken lives...
Positioned on a wall...
With a rifle.
Then the Stasi came calling.
They said,
"your country needs you."
They always say that.
Hmm.
For my country,
I left my country...
And killed wherever
they sent me.
For that,
I was called a monster.
Even the blackest heart
still beats.
I was you, Kohl.
Revenge won't help.
24 years...
They kept me
buried in that hellhole.
I thought about nothing
but today.
What about tomorrow?
I have to see her...
My Anja.
The brachial plexus
is a network of nerves.
Ulrich was always gone
for work,
but when he was with me,
he loved me...
And I loved him.
I was the wife of a spy.
I knew he couldn't talk
about what he did.
Then one day he came home
and said the Stasi
had turned on him.
So then you fled
to the Soviet Union.
He thought
it was still safe there.
We traveled separately.
That's when
the Americans found me.
Then they showed me photos.
Of all the assassinations.
I told myself
that he had lied first.
So much death...
How could he?
The Americans staged
the car accident
to keep me safe.
Ulrich believed I was dead.
But I started a new life.
This could take all night.
She has my mother's eyes.
Don't do
anything stupid, Ulrich.
You hid this?
Her name is Marie.
You're not a monster
to her yet.
It's too late for you and me,
but she could have
a normal life.
How could
she keep this from me?
Anja--
How could she take...
How could they...
Take this girl from me?
That girl could have a chance.
Just leave her be.
As one professional
to another...
I respect
what you have tried to do,
but I can't have you
following me.
Wouldn't worry.
You aren't going anywhere.
Fusco, untie me.
Where do you think he's going?
To find his daughter.
Oh, good night.
- See you later.
- Bye, you guys.
Have fun. Call me tomorrow.
Excuse me, miss.
Can you help me?
I'm looking for Lerner Hall.
Oh, yeah.
Sure, um...
You need to call your mother.
- Marie?
- Mom...
There's a man here with me.
He wants to talk to you.
Kohl wants to meet in the park.
He said he wouldn't hurt
the girl if his wife came alone.
She's not going anywhere alone.
Please don't hurt me.
I just need to speak
to your mother,
and then this will all be over.
- How do you know her?
- From the past.
I knew her.
I knew your father.
My father?
Did your mother tell you
about him?
He was a soldier in Germany...
Before she moved here.
He was a brave man.
He died before I was born.
He died a hero.
A hero?
After the Berlin wall fell,
he helped her get out.
He helped her get free
so she and I could start
a life here.
Did you know my father?
I did...
Once.
All units be advised--
Possible abduction in
the vicinity of Central Park.
Perpetrator,
male, age 60-plus.
Victim--
Female, age 23.
I'm really sorry about this...
More sorry
than you'll ever know.
Where is your friend?
He's right here.
Where you been?
We got an anonymous call.
Our shooter's in the park?
If he's here,
I got a feeling
my vigilante's here, too.
Think we'll get them both?
Why don't the two of you
go with him?
Come on.
Why?
Why did you go?
I found out my husband
wasn't the man I married.
He was a killer.
I was trapped and pregnant.
I thought I knew him...
But they told me
he had become a monster.
Mom...
Who is this man?
I was afraid of the person
you had become.
Can you forgive me
for the person I was?
I had to see your face...
To see both of your faces.
You told her
about her father--
That he was a hero,
that he saved you.
Without him...
We wouldn't have had
this life--
Either of us.
A part of me
has been with you always.
Ulrich.
This is Carter--
Report.
Who has a 20 on that shot?
Are you all right?
Ulrich, no.
No, no.
Finch, get them out of here.
You were right to fear me.
You were right.
Empty.
I wouldn't have hurt her.
I never had a tomorrow.
How did you know I'd shoot?
You are a soldier, like me.
They took everything I had.
But part of me survived.
It was...
Her.
All units, we've
located source of that shot.
Shooter--
Male, down, dead.
Bravo team leader, report in.
Who'd you think it was, Carter?
Harper.
No, not a Harper.
I need you to dispose of this
and them.
You didn't even question them.
We don't have time
for questions--
Only answers.
These men took a bribe
to let a mass murderer escape.
How do we know it was them?
Anonymous source--
Very reliable.
You need to know this is right?
I'll tell you one last time
before it gets complicated.
This is right.
The threat is real.
Your country needs you.
No teeth, no fingertips.
One last thing...
You don't have any old friends.
You see them...
You don't know them.
We're walking in the dark here,
you understand?
I think I've got it.
You'll be...
Mr. Reese.
After all that,
he goes in the ground
under a name
that isn't even his.
The German government will sweep
the whole thing under the rug.
And Ulrich Kohl never existed.
I always thought I'd die
in a place
that didn't know my name.
You think anyone
will care for our names?
After we're dead.
I thought we already were.
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com